A Guide to the Records of the Office of Vice President, Charles Clement French, 1949-1950
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Charles Clement French, Records of the Office of the Vice President, 1949-1950
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 3/2
2 boxes; 2.8 cu. ft.
Charles Clement French served as Vice President of the Virginia Polytechnic Institute from January 1949 through August 1950. The collection contains primarily correspondence but also materials related to the American Chemical Society of Virginia, American Council on Education, Board of Control of Southern Regional Education; Educational Policy and Program Committee; General Education Board; and student alcohol consumption. Also included are travel vouchers and budget materials.
Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Blacksburg, Virginia, Office of the Vice President
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Biographical Information
Charles Clement French assumed the vice-presidency in mid-January 1949. He resigned the position in August 1950 to become dean of the Texas Agricultural and Mechanical College.
Scope and Content
This collection is primarily correspondence, but also includes materials related to: American Chemical Society of Virginia Blue Ridge Section; American Council on Education; Board of Control of Southern Regional Education; Educational Policy and Program Committee; General Education Board; and student alcohol consumption. There are several letters dealing with Graduate Engineering Summer School. Among faculty correspondence contained in the collection are letters to and from C.H. Cowgill, B.N. Cooper, Frank Horsfall, and T.B. Hutcheson. Also included in the collection are travel vouchers and budget materials.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
- Admissions Office: Dr. Farrier, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- American Council on Education, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- American Chemical Society Virginia Blue Ridge Section, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Applications by Chinese Students for Financial Aid USDS, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Applied Mechanics - Summer School University Representatives, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Applied Mechanics - Summer School University Representatives, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Board of Control of Southern Regional Education: John E. Ivey, et. al, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Board of Control of Southern Regional Education: John E. Ivey, et. al, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Board of Control of Southern Regional Education: John E. Ivey, et. al, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Board of Control of Southern Regional Education: John E. Ivey, et. al, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Budget Information, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Cato, W.H. - Director, Guidance and Placement, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Committee - Regarding Drinking, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Cooper, B.N. - Geology, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence: Students and Families, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Cowgill, C.H. - Architectural Engineer, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Disciplinary Committee - French, Munford and Bates, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Educational Policy and Program Committee, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- F - General, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Faculty Adjustments - Pending, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Faculty Appointments - Academic Science, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Faculty Appointments - Agriculture, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Faculty Appointments - Engineering, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Faculty Appointments - Engineering, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Faculty Appointments - Engineering, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Faculty Leaves of Absence, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Faculty - Resignations, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Faculty - Regarding Rules and Regulations, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Faculty - Summer School, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- French, C. Clement - Expense Accounts, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Freshman Course Advisors, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- G - General, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- General Education Board, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Graduate Committee, Etc., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Graduate Faculty, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Graduate Information - New Orleans Meeting, November 13-17, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Graduate Information - New Orleans Meeting, November 13-17, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Hatcher, T.W. - Mathematics, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Horsfall, Frank - Horticulture, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Hutcheson, Dean T.B. - Agriculture, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Institute of International Education Fulbright Act, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- J - General, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Library - Seymour Robb, Librarian, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- M - General, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Manning, H.L. - Industrial Engineering, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- McNeil, R.H. - Public Relations, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Military, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Military, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Mimeographed Material by Dr. C. Clement French, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Munford, T.W. - Military Science, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Murray, W.A. - Electrical Engineering, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Newman, Dr. Walter S. - President, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Norris, Dean E.B. - Engineering, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Personnel - Faculty, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Personnel Office, Richmond Correspondence, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Pletta, D.H. - Applied Mechanics, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Questionnaires - Answered, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Regional Council for Education, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- S - General, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Sanders, H.W. - Vocational Education, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Slusher, Miss Clarice - Registrar, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Southern Association of Colleges and Universities, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- State Board of Education, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Student Life Committee, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Summer School Staff, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 65)
- T - General, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- Tate, Mildred - Home Economics, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 67)
- Veterinary Medicine Data, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 68)
- Vilbrandt, F.C. - Chemical Engineer, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Watson, J.W. - Chemistry, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 70)